Graeme O'Geran Presidential Autograph Collection
Graeme O'Geran Presidential Autograph Collection
1783-1991
O'Geran, Graeme.
2 linear ft.
Autographs of the first 41 presidents of the United States (Washington through George H. W. Bush) and a few of other notable individuals (among them Edison, Ford, and Firestone). Signed items include letters, documents and photographs.
2727989
Biographical History
Graeme O'Geran was a Professor of Economics in the Maxwell School of Public Affairs and Citizenship at Syracuse University.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Graeme O'Geran Presidential Autograph Collection contains signed documents, letters or photographs from the first 41 presidents of the United States (from Washington to George H. W. Bush).
Also in the collection are a few autographs of miscellaneous other individuals; notable here is a group photo of Henry Ford, Thomas Edison, and Harvey Firestone, signed by all three men.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is in chronological order of their presidency.
Related Material
has several other collections of autographs. See for example the following:
Argosy Autograph Collection
Frances Ward Harrington Autograph Collection
Howes Norris, Jr. Autograph Cartoon Collection
Gordon N. Ray Collection of Victorian Autographs
Fremont Rider Autograph Collection
Subject and Genre Headings
Science and medicine; Politics, government and public administration; Adams, John, 1735-1826.; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848.; Arthur, Chester Alan, 1829-1886.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868.; Bush, George, 1924-; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Fillmore, Millard, 1800-1874.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901.; Harrison, William Henry, 1773-1841.; Hayes, Rutherford B., 1822-1893.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.; Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Madison, James, 1749-1812.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Pierce, Franklin, 1804-1869.; Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849.; Reagan, Ronald.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Taylor, Zachary, 1784-1850.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Inventors -- Autographs.; Presidents of the United States -- Autographs.; Autographs -- Collections.; Autographs.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Graeme O'Geran, 1990, 1991.
Inventory
- Presidential autographs
  - Washington, George, discharge papers for Private John Garrison (Box 1)
  - Adams, John, 1823; document (Box 1)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1797; letter (Box 1)
  - Madison, James, 1815; Revolutionary War land grant (Oversize 1)
  - Monroe, James, 1783; note (Box 1)
  - Adams, John Quincy, 1835; letter to Parkman (Box 1)
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1827; letter (Box 1)
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1842; letter (Box 1)
  - Harrison, William Henry, 1796; document (Box 1)
  - Tyler, John, 1840; letter (Box 1)
  - Polk, James, 1847; letter, note (Box 1)
  - Taylor, Zachary, 1835; letter, Fort Crawford (Box 1)
  - Filmore, Millard, 1852; letter (Box 1)
  - Pierce, Franklin, letter to Robert McClellan, Sec. of Interior (Box 1)
  - Buchanan, James, 1858; letter of introduction (Box 1)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1865; letter on executive stationery (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Andrew, 1865; letter, document (Box 1)
    See Oversize 1 for document.
  - Grant, Ulysses S., photograph, letter (Box 1)
  - Garfield, James, 1877; letter (Box 1)
  - Arthur, Chester A., 1844; letter (Box 1)
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1840; letter (Box 1)
  - Cleveland, Grover, 1885; letter (Box 1)
  - McKinley, William, 1898; undated; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1905; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1920; 1912; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1897; letter, program (Box 1)
  - Harding, Warren G., 1906; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1923; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Hoover, Herbert C., 1933; letter; photograph, inscribed (Box 1)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1939; letter; photograph, inscribed (Box 1)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1947; letter (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., photograph in uniform (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, John F., photograph (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., photograph (Box 1)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1960; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Ford, Gerald, 1974; undated; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Carter, Jimmy, letter, photograph; photo also signed by Mrs. Carter (Box 1)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1976; undated; letter, photograph (Box 1)
  - Bush, George H. W., 1991; letter (Box 1)
- Other
  - Miscellaneous, 11 items (Box 1)